<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Note StyleSheet="xml/default_style.xml">    
    <Header MarginBottom="2%">
        <Title>DOUBT</Title>
        <Speaker>Todd Clark</Speaker>
        <Date>April 11th &amp; 12th, 2015</Date>
    </Header>

    <P MarginTop="2%">The question is not will you have <RB>DOUBTS</RB>; the question is what do you <RB>DO</RB>  <RB>WITH</RB> <RB>YOUR</RB> <RB>DOUBTS?</RB></P>
    
    <Q Citation="Matthew 11" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/mat.11.niv">At that time Jesus said, &quot;I praise you, Father, Lord of heaven and earth, because you have hidden these things from the wise and learned, and revealed them to little children.&quot;</Q>

    <Q Citation="Mark 6" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/mrk.6.niv">Jesus left there and went to his hometown, accompanied by his disciples. When the Sabbath came, he began to teach in the synagogue, and many who heard him were amazed. &quot;Where did this man get these things?&quot; they asked. &quot;What’s this wisdom that has been given him? What are these remarkable miracles he is performing? Isn’t this the carpenter?&quot;</Q>


    <L>
        <LI>
            <P>It is <RB>NORMAL</RB> to have doubts.</P>
        </LI>

        <LI>
            <P>God does not <RB>KICK</RB> <RB>YOU</RB> <RB>OUT</RB> when you doubt.</P>

            <Q Citation="2 Timothy 2:13" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/2ti.2.8-13.niv">Here is a trustworthy saying: If we died with him, we will also live with him; if we endure, we will also reign with him. If we disown him, he will also disown us; if we are faithless, he remains faithful, for he cannot disown himself.</Q>
        </LI>

        <LI>
            <P>Faith built on <RB>FEELINGS</RB> will eventually <RB>FALL</RB></P>

            <Q Citation="Hebrews 12:2-3" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/heb.12.1-3.niv">Fixing our eyes on Jesus, the pioneer and perfecter of faith. For the joy set before him he endured the cross, scorning its shame, and sat down at the right hand of the throne of God. Consider him who endured such opposition from sinners, so that you will not grow weary and lose heart.</Q>
        </LI>
    </L>
	
</Note>
