<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Note StyleSheet="xml/default_style.xml">    
    <Header MarginBottom="2%">
        <Title>WHAT HAPPENS WHEN WE DIE?</Title>
        <Speaker>Dr. Don Wilson</Speaker>
        <Date>May 30th &amp; 31st, 2015</Date>
    </Header>

    <P MarginTop="15%">We will all face <RB>JUDGEMENT.</RB></P>
    <Q Citation="Hebrews 9:27" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/heb.9.11-27.niv">Man is destined to die once, and after that to face judgment.</Q>

    <P MarginTop="15%">We will all be judged according to how we <RB>LIVED</RB> our lives.</P>
    <Q Citation="2 Corinthians 5:10" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/2co.5.1-10.niv">For we must all appear before the judgment seat of Christ, that each one may 
                                                                                           receive what is due him for the things done while in the body, whether good or bad.</Q>
    <P MarginTop="15%">We will all spend eternity in <RB>HEAVEN</RB> or <RB>HELL.</RB></P>
    <P MarginTop="5%" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/luk.16.19-31.niv"> Tap To Read:</P>
    <P> Luke 16:39 - The Rich Man and Lazarus</P>

    <P MarginTop="15%">What is heaven like?</P>
    <Q Citation="Revelation 21:3-4" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/rev.21.1-8.niv">
        And I heard a loud voice from the throne saying, &apos;Now the dwelling of God is with men, and he will live with them. They will be his people, and God himself will be with them and be their God.
        He will wipe every tear from their eyes. There will be no more death or mourning or crying or pain, for the old order of things has passed away.&apos;
    </Q>
    
    <Q Citation="Psalm 16:11" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/psa.16.niv">
        You will show me the way of life, granting me the joy of your presence and the pleasures of living with you forever.
    </Q>
    
    <P MarginTop="15%">What is hell like?</P>
    <Q Citation="2 Thessalonians 1:7-9" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/2th.1.niv">
        This will happen when the Lord Jesus is revealed from heaven in blazing fire with his powerful angels. 
        He will punish those who do not know God and do not obey the gospel of our Lord Jesus. 
        They will be punished with everlasting destruction and shut out from the presence of the Lord.
    </Q>

    <L MarginTop="5%" Type="Bullet">
        <LI>
            <P>All of us will die and face the <RB>JUDGEMENT.</RB></P>
        </LI>

        <LI>
            <P>Heave and hell are <RB>REAL</RB> places.</P>
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>Our location in eternity is <RB>PERMANENT.</RB></P>
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P><RB>URGENCY</RB> is needed because life is short and death is certain.</P>
        </LI>
    </L>
</Note>
