<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Note StyleSheet="xml/default_style.xml">    
    <Header MarginBottom="2%">
        <Title>WHY DOES GOD ALLOW SUFFERING?</Title>
        <Speaker>Dr. Don Wilson</Speaker>
        <Date>May 16th &amp; 17th, 2015</Date>
    </Header>

    <Q Citation="John 16:33" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/jhn.16.16-33.niv">In this world you will have trouble.</Q>

    <P MarginTop="15%">GOD&apos;s PLAN - He created a <RB>PERFECT</RB> world.</P>
    <Q Citation="Genesis 1:31" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/gen.1.28-31.niv">God saw all that he had made, and it was very good.</Q>


    <P MarginTop="15%">OUR PROBLEM - We have <RB>ABUSED</RB> our free will.</P>

    <L MarginTop="5%" Type="Bullet">
        <LI>
            <P><RB>MORAL</RB> evil</P>
            <Q Citation="Romans 3:23" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/rom.3.21-26.niv">For all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God.</Q>
        </LI>

        <LI>
            <P><RB>NATURAL</RB> evil</P>
            <Q Citation="Romans 8:22" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/rom.8.18-25.niv">We know that the whole creation has been groaning as in the pains of childbirth right up to the present time.</Q>
        </LI>
    </L>



    <P MarginTop="15%">GOD&apos;s PURPOSE - He wants to bring <RB>GOOD</RB> out of suffering.</P>
    <Q Citation="Romans 8:28" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/rom.8.18-28.niv">And we know that in all things God works for the good of those who love him, who have been called according to his purpose.</Q>



    <P MarginTop="15%">OUR PERSPECTIVE - We must think <RB>LONG</RB> term.</P>
    <Q Citation="Romans 8:18" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/rom.8.18-28.niv">I consider that our present sufferings are not worth comparing with the glory that will be revealed in us.</Q>

    <Q Citation="1 Corinthians 2:9" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/1co.2.6-10.niv">No eye has seen, nor ear has heard, no mind has conceived what God has prepared for those who love him.</Q>



    <P MarginTop="15%">GOD&apos;s DESIRE - He wants us to <RB>TURN</RB> <RB>TO</RB> him.</P>
    <Q Citation="John 16:33" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/jhn.16.16-33.niv">I have told you these things, so that in me you may have peace. In this world you will have trouble. But take heart! I have overcome the world.</Q>

    <L MarginTop="5%" Type="Bullet">
        <LI>
            <P>He gives us <RB>PEACE</RB> to deal with our present.</P>
        </LI>

        <LI>
            <P>He gives us <RB>COURAGE</RB> to deal with our future.</P>
        </LI>
    </L>


    <P MarginTop="15%">TAKE AWAY - Are you <RB>READY?</RB></P>
    <Q Citation="1 John 5:13" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/1jn.5.13-21.niv">I write these things to you who believe in the name of the Son of God so that you may know that you have eternal life.</Q>
    
</Note>
