<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Note StyleSheet="xml/default_style.xml">    
    <Header MarginBottom="2%">
        <Title>CHURCH</Title>
        <Speaker>Dr. Don Wilson</Speaker>
        <Date>Mar 28th &amp; 29th, 2015</Date>
    </Header>

    <L Type="Numbered">
        <LI>
            <P>Penetration - we must be <RB>FOCUSED</RB></P>
            <Q Citation="Matthew 5:13-16" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/97/mat.5.13-16.msg">You are the salt of the earth. But if the salt loses its saltiness, how can it be made salty again? It is no longer good for anything, except to be thrown out and trampled by men. You are the light of the world. A city on a hill cannot be hidden. Neither do people light a lamp and put it under a bowl. Instead they put it on its stand, and it gives light to everyone in the house. In the same way, let your light shine before men that they may see your good deeds and praise your Father in heaven.</Q>

            <L>
                <LI>
                    <P>Find people with similar <RB>LOCATION</RB></P>
                </LI>

                <LI>
                    <P>Find people with similar <RB>INTERESTS</RB></P>
                </LI>

                <LI>
                    <P>Find people in <RB>TRANSITION</RB></P>
                </LI>

                <LI>
                    <P>Find people in <RB>TENSION</RB></P>
                </LI>
            </L>

            <P MarginBottom="5%">Take Away: One <RB>PERSON</RB> I need to focus on:</P>
        </LI>

        <LI>
            <P>Utilization - we must be <RB>FLEXIBLE</RB></P>
            <Q Citation="1 Corinthians 9:19-22 (MSG)" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/97/1co.9.19-23.msg">Even though I am free of the demands and expectations of everyone, I have voluntarily become a servant to any and all in order to reach a wide range of people: religious, nonreligious, meticulous moralists, loose-living immoralists, the defeated, the demoralized - whoever. I didn&apos;t take on their way of life. I kept my bearings in Christ - but I entered their world and tried to experience things from their point of view.</Q>

            <L>
                <LI>
                    <P>In essentials <RB>UNITY</RB></P>
                </LI>

                <LI>
                    <P>In non-essentials <RB>LIBERTY</RB></P>
                </LI>

                <LI>
                    <P>In all things <RB>LOVE</RB></P>
                </LI>
            </L>

            <P MarginBottom="5%">Take Away: One <RB>AREA</RB> I need to be more flexible:</P>
        </LI>

        <LI>
            <P>Mobilization - we must be <RB>SERVANTS</RB></P>
            <Q Citation="Ephesians 4:11-13" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/eph.4.11-16.niv">It was he who gave some to be apostles, some to be prophets, some to be evangelists, and some to be pastors and teachers, to prepare God’s people for works of service, so that the body of Christ may be built up until we all reach unity in the faith and in the knowledge of the Son of God and become mature, attaining to the whole measure of the fullness of Christ.</Q>

            <L>
                <LI>
                    <P>In the Old Testament - God was always <RB>ABOVE</RB> us.</P>
                </LI>

                <LI>
                    <P>In the New Testament - God was always <RB>WITH</RB> us.</P>
                </LI>

                <LI>
                    <P>Today - God is <RB>IN</RB> us.</P>
                </LI>
            </L>

            <P MarginBottom="5%">Take Away: One <RB>MINISTRY</RB> where I need to serve:</P>
        </LI>

    </L>
    
</Note>
