<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<Note Padding="5%" StyleSheet="xml/default_style.xml">

    <Header>
        <Title>THINK BIG</Title>
        <Speaker>Dr. Don Wilson</Speaker>
        <Date>August 1st &amp; 2nd, 2015</Date>
    </Header>
    
    <Q Citation="2 Samuel 23:20-23" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/2sa.23.niv">
        20. Benaiah son of Jehoiada, a valiant fighter from Kabzeel, performed great exploits. 
        He struck down Moab’s two mightiest warriors. He also went down into a pit on a snowy day and killed a lion. 
        21. And he struck down a huge Egyptian. Although the Egyptian had a spear in his hand, Benaiah went against him 
        with a club. He snatched the spear from the Egyptian’s hand and killed him with his own spear. 
        22. Such were the exploits of Benaiah son of Jehoiada; he too was as famous as the three mighty warriors.
        23. He was held in greater honor than any of the Thirty, but he was not included among the Three. 
        And David put him in charge of his bodyguard.
    </Q>
     
    <L MarginTop="5%">
        <LI>
            <P>Past experiences prepare us for future <RB>OPPORTUNITIES.</RB></P>
        </LI>
        <LI>
            <P>Opportunities are often disguised as <RB>PROBLEMS.</RB></P>
        </LI>
        <LI>
            <P>You must <RB>TRUST</RB> <RB>GOD</RB> regardless of the size of your problem.</P>
            <Q Citation="Judges 7:1-22" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/jdg.7.niv">
                1. Early in the morning, Jerub-Baal (that is, Gideon) and all his men camped at the spring of Harod. 
                The camp of Midian was north of them in the valley near the hill of Moreh. 
                2. The Lord said to Gideon, &quot;You have too many men. I cannot deliver Midian into their hands, 
                or Israel would boast against me, &apos;My own strength has saved me.&apos;&quot;
            </Q>
        </LI>
        <LI>
            <P>The bigger God gets, the <RB>SMALLER</RB> the problem becomes.</P>
            <Q Citation="2 Kings 6:1-7" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/2ki.6.niv">
                1. The company of the prophets said to Elisha, 
                &quot;Look, the place where we meet with you is too small for us. 
                2. Let us go to the Jordan, where each of us can get a pole; and let us build a place there for us to meet.&quot;
                And he said, &quot;Go.&quot;
                3. Then one of them said, &quot;Won&apos;t you please come with your servants?&quot;
                &quot;I will,&qut; Elisha replied. 
                4. And he went with them. They went to the Jordan and began to cut down trees. 
                5. As one of them was cutting down a tree, the iron axhead fell into the water. 
                &quot;Oh no, my lord!&quot; he cried out. &quot;It was borrowed!&quot;
                6. The man of God asked, &quot;Where did it fall?&quot; When he showed him the place, 
                Elisha cut a stick and threw it there, and made the iron float. 
                7. &quot;Lift it out,&quot; he said. Then the man reached out his hand and took it.
            </Q>
        </LI>
    </L>
    
    <P MarginTop="10%">TAKE AWAY: In what area of your life do you need to trust God to <RB>STRETCH</RB> your <RB>FAITH?</RB></P>
</Note>
