<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<Note Padding="5%" StyleSheet="xml/default_style.xml">

    <Header>
        <Title>PAIN</Title>
        <Speaker>Dr. Mark Moore</Speaker>
        <Date>July 11th &amp; 12th, 2015</Date>
    </Header>
    
    <Q MarginTop="5%" Citation="Revelation 5 - 9" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/rev.5.niv"/>
    
    <P MarginTop="5%">Are we in the last days?</P>
    <P MarginTop="5%" FontName="OpenSans-Bold">Change the Question:</P>
    <P MarginTop="2%">How do I <RB>SURVIVE</RB> <RB>TODAY?</RB></P>
    
    
    <L MarginTop="5%">
        <LI>
            <P>Take <RB>RESPONSIBILITY.</RB></P>
            <Q Citation="Revelation 5:6" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/rev.5.niv">
                Then I saw a Lamb, looking as if it had been slain, standing at the center of the throne, 
                encircled by the four living creatures and the elders. 
                The Lamb had seven horns and seven eyes, which are the seven spirits of God sent out into all the earth.
            </Q>
        </LI>
        <LI>
            <P>Stop <RB>BEATING</RB> <RB>YOURSELF</RB> up.</P>
            <Q Citation="Revelation 5:10" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/rev.5.niv">
                You have made them to be a kingdom and priests to serve our God,
                and they will reign on the earth.
            </Q>
        </LI>
        <LI>
            <P>Don&apos;t take it <RB>PERSONALLY.</RB></P>
            <Q Citation="Revelation 6:1-8" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/rev.6.niv">
                1. I watched as the Lamb opened the first of the seven seals. Then I heard one of the four living creatures say in a voice like thunder, &quot;Come!&quot; 
                2. I looked, and there before me was a white horse! Its rider held a bow, and he was given a crown, and he rode out as a conqueror bent on conquest.
                3. When the Lamb opened the second seal, I heard the second living creature say, &quot;Come!&quot; 
                4. Then another horse came out, a fiery red one. Its rider was given power to take peace from the earth and to make people kill each other. To him was given a large sword.
                5. When the Lamb opened the third seal, I heard the third living creature say, &quot;Come!&quot; I looked, and there before me was a black horse! 
                Its rider was holding a pair of scales in his hand. 
                6. Then I heard what sounded like a voice among the four living creatures, saying, &quot;Two pounds of wheat for a day’s wages, and six pounds of barley for a day’s wages, and do not damage the oil and the wine!&quot;
                7. When the Lamb opened the fourth seal, I heard the voice of the fourth living creature say, &quot;Come!&quot; 
                8. I looked, and there before me was a pale horse! Its rider was named Death, and Hades was following close behind him. They were given power over a fourth of the earth to kill by sword, 
                famine and plague, and by the wild beasts of the earth.
            </Q>
        </LI>
        <LI>
            <P>Find your <RB>PURPOSE.</RB></P>
            <Q Citation="Revelation 6:9-11" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/rev.6.niv">
                9. When he opened the fifth seal, I saw under the altar the souls of those who had been slain because of the word of God and the testimony they had maintained. 
                10. They called out in a loud voice, &quot;How long, Sovereign Lord, holy and true, until you judge the inhabitants of the earth and avenge our blood?&quot; 
                11. Then each of them was given a white robe, and they were told to wait a little longer, until the full number of their fellow servants, their brothers and sisters, 
                were killed just as they had been.
            </Q>
        </LI>
        <LI>
            <P>Find your <RB>COMMUNITY.</RB></P>
            <Q Citation="Revelation 7:9" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/rev.7.niv">
                After this I looked, and there before me was a great multitude that no one could count, 
                from every nation, tribe, people and language, standing before the throne and before the Lamb. 
                They were wearing white robes and were holding palm branches in their hands.
            </Q>
        </LI>
        <LI>
            <P>Release your <RB>RIGHT</RB> to <RB>REVENGE.</RB></P>
            <Q Citation="Revelation 6:15-17" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/rev.6.niv">
                15. Then the kings of the earth, the princes, the generals, the rich, the mighty, and everyone else, both slave and free, hid in caves and among the rocks of the mountains. 
                16. They called to the mountains and the rocks, &quot;Fall on us and hide us from the face of him who sits on the throne and from the wrath of the Lamb! 
                17. For the great day of their wrath has come, and who can withstand it?&quot;
            </Q>
        </LI>
        <LI>
            <P>Remember you&apos;re <RB>REMEMBERED.</RB></P>
            <Q Citation="Revelation 7:1-4" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/rev.7.niv">
                1. After this I saw four angels standing at the four corners of the earth, holding back the four winds of the earth to prevent any wind from blowing on the land or on the sea or on any tree. 
                2. Then I saw another angel coming up from the east, having the seal of the living God. He called out in a loud voice to the four angels who had been given power to harm the land and the sea: 
                3. &quot;Do not harm the land or the sea or the trees until we put a seal on the foreheads of the servants of our God.&quot; 
                4. Then I heard the number of those who were sealed: 144,000 from all the tribes of Israel.
            </Q>
        </LI>
    </L>
    
    <P MarginTop="15%">TAKE AWAY: Find a <RB>FRIEND</RB> to help identify your <RB>FIRST</RB> <RB>STEP.</RB></P>
</Note>
