<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Note StyleSheet="xml/default_style.xml">    
    <Header MarginBottom="5%">
        <Title>FAMILY</Title>
        <Speaker>Dr. Don Wilson</Speaker>
        <Date>Jan 17th &amp; 18th, 2015</Date>
    </Header>

    <Paragraph MarginBottom="5%">VALUES GOD DESIRES</Paragraph>

    <List Type="Numbered">
    	<ListItem>
			<P>The world values tolerance - God values <RevealBox>TRUTH</RevealBox></P>

			<Quote Citation="John 14:6" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/jhn.14.5-14.niv">
				I am the way and the truth and the life. No man comes to the Father except through me.
			</Quote>

			<Quote Citation="Deuteronomy 6:6-9 (MSG)" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/97/deu.6.6-12.msg">
				Write these commandments that I&apos;ve given you today on your hearts. Get them inside of you and then get them inside your children. Talk about them wherever you are, sitting at home or walking in the street; talk about them from the time you get up in the morning to when you fall into bed at night. Tie them on your hands and foreheads as a reminder; inscribe them on the doorposts of your homes and on your city gates.
			</Quote>

			<List Type="Bullet">
				<ListItem>
					<P>Be <RB>INTENTIONAL</RB></P>
				</ListItem>

				<ListItem>
					<P>Be <RB>INFORMAL</RB></P>
				</ListItem>

				<ListItem>
					<P>Be <RB>INSPIRATIONAL</RB></P>
				</ListItem>
			</List>
		</ListItem>

		<ListItem>
			<P>The world values affulence - God values <RevealBox>GENEROSITY</RevealBox></P>

			<Quote Citation="Luke 12:15" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/luk.12.13-21.niv">
				Be on your guard against all kinds of greed; a man&apos;s life does not consist in the abundance of his posessions.
			</Quote>

			<Quote Citation="Psalm 119:36-37 (MSG)" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/97/psa.119.33-40.msg">
				Give me a bent for your words of wisdom, and not for piling up loot. Divert my eyes from toys and trinkets...
			</Quote>
		</ListItem>

		<ListItem>
			<P>The world values achievement - God values <RB>RELATIONSHIPS</RB></P>

			<Quote Citation="1 Thessalonians 3:12" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/1th.3.6-12.niv">
				May the Lord make your love increase and overflow for each other and for everyone else.
			</Quote>

			<List Type="Bullet">
				<ListItem>
					<P><RB>CARETAKER</RB> - Provide and Protect</P>
				</ListItem>

				<ListItem>
					<P><RB>COACH</RB> - Instruct and Influence</P>
				</ListItem>

				<ListItem>
					<P><RB>COUNSELOR</RB> - Listen and Lead</P>
				</ListItem>

				<ListItem>
					<P><RB>CONFIDANT</RB> - Advise and Affirm</P>
				</ListItem>
			</List>
		</ListItem>

		<ListItem>
			<P>The world values power - God values <RevealBox>SERVICE</RevealBox></P>

			<Quote Citation="Matthew 23:11-12" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/mat.23.1-12.niv">
				Jesus said, &apos;The greatest among you will be your servant. For whoever exalts himself will be humbled, and whoever humbles himself will be exalted.&apos;
			</Quote>
		</ListItem>

		<ListItem>
			<P>The world values appearance - God values <RevealBox>CHARACTER</RevealBox></P>

			<Quote Citation="1 Samuel 16:7" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/1sa.16.3-10.niv">
				The Lord said to Samuel, &apos;Do not consider his appearance or his height, for I have rejected him. The Lord does not look at the things man looks at. Man looks at the outward appearance, but the Lord looks at the heart.&apos;
			</Quote>
		</ListItem>

		<ListItem>
			<P>The world values leisure - God values <RB>WORSHIP</RB></P>

			<Quote Citation="Jeremiah 29:13" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/jer.29.11-14.niv">
				You will seek me and find me when you seek me with all your heart.
			</Quote>

			<Quote Citation="Revelation 3:15-17,19 (MSG)" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/97/rev.3.14-22.msg">
				I know you inside and out, and find little to my liking. You&apos;re not cold, you&apos;re not hot - far better to be either cold or hot! You&apos;re stale. You&apos;re stagnant. You make me want to vomit. You brag, &apos;I&apos;m rich, I&apos;ve got it made, I need nothing from anyone.&apos; Oblivious that in fact you&apos;re a pitiful, blind beggar, threadbare and homeless...The people I love, I call to account - prod and correct and guide so that they&apos;ll live at their best...
			</Quote>
		</ListItem>
	</List>	
	
	<Paragraph>TAKE AWAY: Discuss and develop your <RB>TOP THREE</RB> family values.</Paragraph>
	
</Note>
