<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Note StyleSheet="xml/default_style.xml">    
    <Header>
        <Title>Living On The Edge: When Life is Out of Control</Title>
        <Speaker>Dr. Don Wilson</Speaker>
        <Date>August 30 &amp; 31, 2014</Date>
    </Header>
    
    <Canvas Top="5%">
        <Paragraph>What Jesus said about worry:</Paragraph>
        <Paragraph Top="5%" Alignment="Right">Matthew 6:25-34</Paragraph>
    </Canvas>
    
    <List MarginTop="5%" Type="Numbered">  
        <ListItem>
            <Paragraph>Worry is <RevealBox>UNREASONABLE</RevealBox></Paragraph>
            
            <Quote Citation="Vs. 25">
                Do not worry about your life, what you&apos;ll eat or drink; or about your body, what you
                will wear. Is not life more important than food, and the body more important than
                clothes?
            </Quote>
        </ListItem>
        
       <ListItem>
            <Paragraph>Worry is <RevealBox>UNNATURAL</RevealBox></Paragraph>
            
            <Quote Citation="Vs. 26">
                Look at the birds of the air; they do not sow or reap or store away in barns,
                and yet your heavenly Father feeds them. Are you not more important than they?
            </Quote>
            
            <Quote Citation="Vs. 28-29">
                And why do you worry about your clothes? See how the lilies of the field grow. They
                do not labor or spin. Yet I tell you that not even Solomon in all his splendor
                was dressed like one of these.
            </Quote>
        </ListItem>
        
        <ListItem>
            <Paragraph>Worry is <RevealBox>UNHELPFUL</RevealBox></Paragraph>
            
            <Quote Citation="Vs. 27">
                Who of you by worrying can add a single hour to his life?
            </Quote>
        </ListItem>
        
        <ListItem>
            <Paragraph>Worry is<RevealBox>UNNECESSARY</RevealBox></Paragraph>
            
            <Quote Citation="Vs. 30">
                If God clothes the grass of the field, which is here today and tomorrow
                is thrown into the fire, will he not much more clothe you, O you of little faith?
            </Quote>
        </ListItem>
        
        <ListItem>
            <Paragraph>Worry is <RevealBox>UNCHRISTIAN</RevealBox></Paragraph>
            
            <Quote Citation="Vs. 31-32">
                Do not worry, saying &apos;What shall we eat?&apos; or &apos;What shall we drink?&apos; or
                &apos;What shall we wear?&apos; For the pagans run after these things, and your heavenly
                Father knows that you need them.
            </Quote>
        </ListItem>
        
    </List>
    
    <Paragraph MarginTop="5%">The antidote for worry:</Paragraph>
    
    <List MartinTop="5%" Type="Bullet">
        <ListItem>
            <Paragraph>
                Put God <RevealBox>FIRST</RevealBox> in <RevealBox>EVERY</RevealBox> area 
                of your life.
           </Paragraph>
           
           <Quote Citation="Vs. 33">
                Seek first his kingdom and his righteousness, and all these things will be
                given to you as well.
           </Quote>
        </ListItem>
        
        <ListItem>
            <Paragraph>
                Live <RevealBox>ONE </RevealBox> <RevealBox>DAY</RevealBox> at a time.
           </Paragraph>
           
           <Quote Citation="Vs. 34">
                Don&apos;t worry about tomorrow, for tomorrow will worry about itself. Each day 
                has enough trouble of its own.
           </Quote>
        </ListItem>
    </List>

    <Paragraph>TAKE AWAY:</Paragraph>
    <Paragraph><RevealBox>PRAISE</RevealBox> + Poise + <RevealBox>PRAYER</RevealBox> = Peace</Paragraph>
    
    <Quote Citation="Philippians 4:4-8">
        Rejoice in the Lord always. I will say it again: Rejoice! Let your gentleness be evident
        to all. The Lord is near. Do not be anxious about anything, but in everything, by prayer
        and petition, with thanksgiving present your requests to God. And the peace of God, which
        transcends all understanding, will guard your heart and minds in Christ Jesus. Finally
        brothers, whatever is true, noble, right, pure, lovely, admirable; if anything is excellent 
        or praiseworthy, think about such things.
   </Quote>
    
</Note>
