<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<Note Padding="5%" StyleSheet="xml/default_style.xml">

    <Header>
        <Title>RUNNING TO GOD</Title>
        <Speaker>Todd Clark</Speaker>
        <Date>June 13th &amp; 14th, 2015</Date>
    </Header>
    
    
    <Q Citation="Jonah 2" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/jon.2" ChildAlignment="Center">
        From inside the fish Jonah prayed to the Lord his God. He said:
        &quot;In my distress I called to the Lord,
        and he answered me.
        From deep in the realm of the dead I called for help,
        and you listened to my cry.
        You hurled me into the depths,
        into the very heart of the seas,
        and the currents swirled about me;
        all your waves and breakers
        swept over me.
        I said, &apos;I have been banished
        from your sight;
        yet I will look again
        toward your holy temple.&apos;
        The engulfing waters threatened me,
        the deep surrounded me;
        seaweed was wrapped around my head.
        To the roots of the mountains I sank down;
        the earth beneath barred me in forever.
        But you, Lord my God,
        brought my life up from the pit.
        &quot;When my life was ebbing away,
        I remembered you, Lord,
        and my prayer rose to you,
        to your holy temple.
        &quot;Those who cling to worthless idols
        turn away from God’s love for them.
        But I, with shouts of grateful praise,
        will sacrifice to you.
        What I have vowed I will make good.
        I will say, &apos;Salvation comes from the Lord.&apos;&quot;
        And the Lord commanded the fish, and it vomited Jonah onto dry land.
    </Q>
     
     <List>
         <LI>
            <P>It&apos;s never too late to <RB>PRAY</RB></P>
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>God often <RB>ORCHESTRATES</RB> the circumstances that stop us from running.</P>
            <Quote Citation="Jonah 2:8" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/jon.2">
                Those who cling to worthless idols turn away from God&apos;s love for them.
            </Quote>
            <Quote Citation="2 Kings 17:15" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/2ki.17.7-23.niv">
            They rejected his decrees and the covenant he had made with their ancestors and the statutes he had warned them to keep. 
            They followed worthless idols and themselves became worthless. 
            They imitated the nations around them although the Lord had ordered them, &quot;Do not do as they do.&quot;
            </Quote>	
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>God&apos;s <RB>GRACE</RB> is guaranteed.</P>
            <Quote Citation="1 Kings 8:38-39" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/1ki.8.22-61.niv">
                and when a prayer or plea is made by anyone among your people Israel—being aware of the afflictions of their own hearts, 
                and spreading out their hands toward this temple—then hear from heaven, your dwelling place. Forgive and act; deal with everyone according to all they do, since you know their hearts 
                (for you alone know every human heart)
            </Quote>	
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>God&apos;s <RB>DISCIPLINE</RB> is thorough.</P>
            <Quote Citation="Hebrews 12:10-11" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/heb.12.7-13.niv">
                They disciplined us for a little while as they thought best; but God disciplines us for our good, 
                in order that we may share in his holiness. No discipline seems pleasant at the time, but painful. 
                Later on, however, it produces a harvest of righteousness and peace for those who have been trained by it.
            </Quote>	
        </LI>
          
         <LI>
            <P>God is the God of <RB>SECOND</RB> <RB>CHANCES.</RB></P>
        </LI>
    </List>	
    <TextInput Height="200">Text</TextInput>
</Note>
