<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Note StyleSheet="xml/default_style.xml">    
    <Header>
        <Title>Living On The Edge: When Life Is Out Of Balance</Title>
        <Speaker>Dr. Don Wilson</Speaker>
        <Date>August 16 &amp; 17, 2014</Date>
    </Header>
    
    <Quote Citation="Psalm 37:1-7">
        Do not fret because of evil men or be envious of those who do wrong; for like grass they
        will soon wither, like green plants they will soon die away. Trust in the Lord and do good;
        dwell in the land and enjoy safe pasture. Delight yourself in the Lord and he will give you the desires of your heart.
        Commit your way to the Lord; trust in him and he will do this: He will make your righteousness shine like the dawn,
        the justice of your cause like the noonday sun. Be still before the Lord and wait patiently for him...</Quote>
    
    <List MarginTop="5%" Type="Numbered">  
        <ListItem>
            <Paragraph>Commitment gives<RevealBox>STABILITY</RevealBox>to life.</Paragraph>
            
            <List Type="Bullet">
                <ListItem>
                    <Paragraph>Your commitments reflect your <RevealBox>VALUES.</RevealBox></Paragraph>
                </ListItem>
            </List>
            <Quote Citation="Matthew 6:33">
                Seek first his kingdom and his rightesouness, and all these things will be given to you as well.
            </Quote>
        </ListItem>
        
        <ListItem>
            <Paragraph>Trust gives<RevealBox>PEACE</RevealBox>to life.</Paragraph>
            
            <List Type="Bullet">
                <ListItem>
                    <Paragraph>Release things to God palms <RevealBox>DOWN</RevealBox></Paragraph>
                </ListItem>
            </List>
            <Quote Citation="Proverbs 3:5-6">
                Trust in the Lord with all your heart and lean not on your own understanding; in all your ways acknowledge him and he will make your paths straight.
            </Quote>
        </ListItem>
        
        <ListItem>
            <Paragraph>Delight gives<RevealBox>MOMENTUM</RevealBox>to life.</Paragraph>
            
            <Quote Citation="Luke 24:50-52">
                When he had led them out to the vicinity of Bethany, he lifted up his hands and blessed them. While he was belssing themn,
                he left them and was tken up into heaven. Then they worshiped him and returned to Jerusalem with great joy.
            </Quote>
        </ListItem>
        
        
        <ListItem>
            <Paragraph>Rest gives<RevealBox>PERSPECTIVE</RevealBox>to life.</Paragraph>
            
            <List Type="Bullet">
                <ListItem>
                    <Paragraph>God answers our prayers with a <RevealBox>YES, </RevealBox> <RevealBox>NO,</RevealBox> or <RevealBox>WAIT.</RevealBox></Paragraph>
                </ListItem>
            </List>
            <Quote Citation="Psalm 40:1-2">
                I waited patiently for the Lord; he turned to me and heard my cry. He lifted me out of the slimy pit, out of the mud and mire; he set my feet on a rock and gave me a firm place to stand.
            </Quote>
        </ListItem>
    </List>
    

    <Paragraph>
        TAKE AWAY: What is one change you need to make so that <RevealBox>GOD</RevealBox> is your <RevealBox>TOP</RevealBox> priority?          
    </Paragraph>
    
    <TextInput PlaceHolder="Enter takeaway"/>
</Note>
