<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<Note StyleSheet="xml/default_style.xml">

    <Header>
        <Title>BOUNCE BACK</Title>
        <Speaker>Dr. Don Wilson</Speaker>
        <Date>August 22nd &amp; 23rd, 2015</Date>
    </Header>
    
    <Q Alignment="Center" Citation="Luke 5:1-11" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/luk.5.1-11.niv">
    </Q>
    
    <P FontName="OpenSans-Bold">1. Get Jesus in your life.</P>
    <Q Citation="Luke 5:1-3" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/luk.5.1-11.niv">
        1. One day as Jesus was standing by the Lake of Gennesaret, 
        the people were crowding around him and listening to the word of God.
        2. He saw at the water’s edge two boats, left there by the fishermen, who were washing their nets.
        3. He got into one of the boats, the one belonging to Simon, and asked him to put out a little from shore. 
        Then he sat down and taught the people from the boat.
    </Q>
    <L>
        <LI>
            <P>He will change your <RB>PERSPECTIVE.</RB></P>
            <Q Citation="2 Timothy 3:16-17" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/2ti.3.niv">
                16. All Scripture is God-breathed and is useful for teaching, rebuking, 
                correcting and training in righteousness, 17. so that the servant of 
                God may be thoroughly equipped for every good work.
            </Q>
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>He eliminates your fear of <RB>FAILURE.</RB></P>
            <Q Citation="Philippians 4:13" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/php.4.10-20.niv">
                I can do all this through him who gives me strength.
            </Q>
        </LI>
    </L>
       
    <P FontName="OpenSans-Bold">2. Get Jesus in your plans.</P>
    <Q Citation="Luke 5:4-5" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/luk.5.1-11.niv">
        4. When he had finished speaking, he said to Simon, &quot;Put out into deep water, 
        and let down the nets for a catch.&quot;
        5. Simon answered, &quot;Master, we&apos;ve worked hard all night and haven&apos;t caught anything. 
        But because you say so, I will let down the nets.&quot;
    </Q>
    <L>
        <LI>
            <P>His plan involves <RB>RISK.</RB></P>
            
            <SP Padding="2%" BorderWidth="1" BorderColor="#3d3d3dFF" BackgroundColor="#2d2d2dFF" MarginTop="5%">
                <P Url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Wesley_Powell">
                    John Wesley Powell was a man who was not afraid of risk.
                </P>
                <P FontName="OpenSans-Bold" Url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Wesley_Powell">
                    Tap to read about him.
                </P>
            </SP>
            
            
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>His plan requires <RB>OBEDIANCE.</RB></P>
        </LI>
    </L>

    <P FontName="OpenSans-Bold">3. Get direction from Jesus&apos; promise.</P>
    <Q Citation="Luke 5:6" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/luk.5.1-11.niv">
        6. When they had done so, they caught such a large number of fish that their nets began to break.
    </Q>
    <Q Citation="Luke 5:10-11" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/luk.5.1-11.niv">
        10. and so were James and John, the sons of Zebedee, Simon&apos;s partners.
        Then Jesus said to Simon, &quot;Don&apos;t be afraid; from now on you will fish for people.&quot;
        11. So they pulled their boats up on shore, left everything and followed him.
    </Q>
    <L>
        <LI>
            <P>His promise changes your <RB>THINKING.</RB></P>
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>His promise changes your <RB>PRIORITIES.</RB></P>
        </LI>
    </L>
   

    
    <P MarginTop="10%">TAKE AWAY: What&apos;s the <RB>FIRST</RB> <RB>THING</RB> you need to do to bounce back?</P>
    <Q Citation="Proverbs 3:5-6">Trust in the Lord with all your heart, and lean not on your own understanding;
        in all your ways acknowledge him, and he will make your paths straight.
    </Q>
</Note>
