<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<Note Padding="5%" StyleSheet="xml/default_style.xml">

    <Header>
        <Title>RUNNING AGAINST GOD</Title>
        <Speaker>Todd Clark</Speaker>
        <Date>June 27th &amp; 28th, 2015</Date>
    </Header>
    
    
    <Q Citation="Jonah 4" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/jon.4" ChildAlignment="Center">
        1 But to Jonah this seemed very wrong, and he became angry. 
        2 He prayed to the Lord, &quot;Isn&apos;t this what I said, Lord, when I was still at home? That is what I tried to forestall by fleeing to Tarshish. 
        I knew that you are a gracious and compassionate God, slow to anger and abounding in love, a God who relents from sending calamity. 
        3 Now, Lord, take away my life, for it is better for me to die than to live.&quot;
        4 But the Lord replied, &quot;Is it right for you to be angry?&quot;
        5 Jonah had gone out and sat down at a place east of the city. There he made himself a shelter, sat in its shade and waited to see what would happen to the city. 
        6 Then the Lord God provided a leafy plant and made it grow up over Jonah to give shade for his head to ease his discomfort, 
        and Jonah was very happy about the plant. 
        7 But at dawn the next day God provided a worm, which chewed the plant so that it withered. 
        8 When the sun rose, God provided a scorching east wind, and the sun blazed on Jonah&apos;s head so that he grew faint. 
        He wanted to die, and said, &quot;It would be better for me to die than to live.&quot;
        9 But God said to Jonah, &quot;Is it right for you to be angry about the plant?&quot;
        &quot;It is,&quot; he said. &quot;And I’m so angry I wish I were dead.&quot;
        10 But the Lord said, &quot;You have been concerned about this plant, though you did not tend it or make it grow. 
        It sprang up overnight and died overnight. 
        11 And should I not have concern for the great city of Nineveh, in which there are more than a hundred and twenty thousand people who cannot 
        tell their right hand from their left—and also many animals?&quot;
    </Q>
     
     <List>
         <LI>
            <P>Jonah is <RB>OFFENDED</RB> by God&apos;s <RB>GRACE.</RB></P>
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>Jonah is <RB>COMMITTED</RB> to his own <RB>COMFORT.</RB></P>	
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>God wants us to be <RB>CONCERNED</RB> with <RB>ETERNAL</RB> things.</P>	
        </LI>
    </List>	
    <P MarginTop="5%">TAKE AWAY:</P>
    <TextInput Height="200">Text</TextInput>
</Note>
