<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<Note Padding="5%" StyleSheet="xml/default_style.xml">

    <Header>
        <Title>OVERCOME FEAR</Title>
        <Speaker>Dr. Don Wilson</Speaker>
        <Date>August 8th &amp; 9th, 2015</Date>
    </Header>
    
    <P MarginTop="5%" FontName="OpenSans-Bold">What happens when fear overcomes faith?</P>
    
    <L Type="Numbered" MarginTop="5%">
        <LI>
            <P>We rely totally on <RB>HUMAN</RB> wisdom.</P>
            <Q Citation="Numbers 13:28" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/num.13.26-33.niv">
                But the people who live there are powerful, and the cities are fortified and very large. 
                We even saw descendants of Anak there.
            </Q>
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>We <RB>EXAGGERATE</RB> the sitation.</P>
            <Q Citation="Numbers 13:33" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/num.13.26-33.niv">
                We saw the Nephilim there (the descendants of Anak come from the Nephilim). 
                We seemed like grasshoppers in our own eyes, and we looked the same to them.
            </Q>
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>We spread <RB>NEGATIVE</RB> talk.</P>
            <Q Citation="Numbers 13:32" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/num.13.26-33.niv">
                And they spread among the Israelites a bad report about the land they had explored. 
                They said, &quot;The land we explored devours those living in it. 
                All the people we saw there are of great size.&quot; 
            </Q>
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>We have an <RB>UNREALISTIC</RB> view of the past.</P>
            <Q Citation="Numbers 14:4" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/num.14.1-4.niv">And they said to each other, &quot;We should choose a leader and go back to Egypt.&quot;</Q>
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>We <RB>CRITICIZE</RB> proven leaders.</P>
            <Q Citation="Numbers 14:2" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/num.14.1-4.niv">All the Israelites grumbled against Moses and Aaron, 
                and the whole assembly said to them, &quot;If only we had died in Egypt! Or in this wilderness!&quot;</Q>
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>We miss <RB>OPPORTUNITIES</RB> for spiritual growth.</P>
        </LI>
    </L>
    
    <P MarginTop="5%" FontName="OpenSans-Bold">What happens when faith overcomes fear?</P>
    
    <L Type="Numbered" MarginTop="5%">
        <LI>
            <P>We stand up for what is <RB>RIGHT.</RB></P>
            <Q Citation="Daniel 3:12" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/dan.3.niv">
                But there are some Jews whom you have set over the affairs of the province of Babylon—Shadrach, 
                Meshach and Abednego—who pay no attention to you, Your Majesty. They neither serve your gods nor 
                worship the image of gold you have set up.
            </Q>
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>We rely totally on <RB>GOD.</RB></P>
            <Q Citation="Daniel 3:16-18" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/dan.3.niv">
                16. Shadrach, Meshach and Abednego replied to him, &quot;King Nebuchadnezzar, we do not need to defend ourselves 
                before you in this matter. 17. If we are thrown into the blazing furnace, the God we serve is able to deliver us 
                from it, and he will deliver us from Your Majesty’s hand. 18. But even if he does not, we want you to know, 
                Your Majesty, that we will not serve your gods or worship the image of gold you have set up.&quot;
            </Q>
        </LI>
        
        <LI>
            <P>We experience God&apos;s <RB>FAITHFULNESS.</RB></P>
            <Q Citation="Daniel 3:28" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/dan.3.niv">
                Then Nebuchadnezzar said, &quot;Praise be to the God of Shadrach, Meshach and Abednego, 
                who has sent his angel and rescued his servants! They trusted in him and defied the king&apos;s 
                command and were willing to give up their lives rather than serve or worship any god except their own God.
            </Q>
            
            <Q Citation="Isaiah 41:10" Url="https://www.bible.com/bible/111/isa.41.niv">
                So do not fear, for I am with you;
                do not be dismayed, for I am your God.
            </Q>
        </LI>
    </L>
    
    <P MarginTop="10%">TAKE AWAY:</P>
    <TextInput Height="200">Text</TextInput>
</Note>
