<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Note StyleSheet="xml/default_style.xml">    
    <Header MarginBottom="5%">
        <Title>There Is Hope - For Your Workplace</Title>
        <Speaker>Dr. Don Wilson</Speaker>
        <Date>Nov 15th &amp; 16th, 2014</Date>
    </Header>

	<StackPanel MarginBottom="5%" BorderColor="#777777FF" BorderWidth="1" BorderRadius="4">
	    <Quote Citation="1 Corinthians 7:17">
	    	Each one should retain the place in life that the Lord assigned to him and to which God has called him.
	    </Quote>
	</StackPanel>

    <List Type="Numbered">
    	<ListItem>
    		<Paragraph MarginBottom="2%"><RevealBox>SUBMIT</RevealBox></Paragraph>
			<Quote Citation="1 Peter 2:18-21">
				Slaves, submit yoursleves to your masters with all respect, not only to those who are good and considerate, but also to those who are harsh. For it is commendable if a man bears up under the pain of unjust suffering because he is conscious of God. But how is it to your credit if you receive a beating for doing wrong and endure it? But if you suffer for doing good and endure it, this is commendable before God. To this you were called, because Christ suffered for you, leaving you an example, that you should follow in his steps.
			</Quote>
		</ListItem>

		<ListItem>
    		<Paragraph MarginBottom="2%"><RevealBox>SUFFER</RevealBox></Paragraph>
		</ListItem>

		<ListItem>
    		<Paragraph MarginBottom="2%"><RevealBox>SHINE</RevealBox></Paragraph>
			<Quote Citation="Ephesians 6:5-9">
				Slaves, obey your earthly masters with respect and fear, and with sincerity of heart, just as you would obey Christ. Obey them not only to win their favor when their eye is on you, but like slaves in Christ, doing the will of God from your heat. Serve wholeheartedly, as if you were serving the Lord, not men, because you know that the Lord will reward everyone for whatever good he does, whether he is slave or free. And masters, treat your sleaves in the same way. Do not threaten them, since you know that he who is both their Master and yours is in heaven, and there is no favoritism with him.
			</Quote>
		</ListItem>

		<ListItem>
    		<Paragraph MarginBottom="2%"><RevealBox>SHARE</RevealBox></Paragraph>
			<Quote Citation="1 Peter 3:15">
				Always be prepared to give an answer to everyone who asks you to give the reason for the hope that you have. But do this with gentleness and respect.
			</Quote>
		</ListItem>
	</List>

	<TextInput PlaceHolder="Takeaway"></TextInput>

</Note>